[
    {
        "question": "This radial distance in a gear is measured between the addendum and dedendum circle, and is the sum of the addendum and the dedendum? How do you call this distance?",
        "choices": ["Addendum", "Whole depth", "Working depth", "Space width"],
        "answer": "Whole depth"
    },
    {
        "question": "This minimum distance is measured between the non-driving side of a tooth and the adjacent side of the mating tooth. It is the amount by which the width of a tooth space exceeds the thickness of the engaging tooth measured on the pitch circle. What is this distance?",
        "choices": ["Circular pitch", "Whole depth", "Backlash", "Space width"],
        "answer": "Backlash"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you call the diameter of the imaginary cylinder that bounds the crest of an external thread and the roots of an internal thread?",
        "choices": ["Mean diameter", "Stress diameter", "Minor diameter", "Major diameter"],
        "answer": "Major diameter"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you call the circle on a gear that corresponds to the contact surface of the friction wheel?",
        "choices": ["Addendum circle", "Root circle", "Pitch circle", "Base circle"],
        "answer": "Pitch circle"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest roller chain size that can be used for power transmission at a sprocket speed of 1000 rpm?",
        "choices": ["RC 35", "RC 50", "RC 80", "RC 60"],
        "answer": "RC 60"
    },
    {
        "question": "These are gears with teeth formed on conical surfaces and are used mostly for transmitting motion between intersecting shafts. How do you call these gears?",
        "choices": ["Spur gears", "Bevel gears", "Helical gears", "Worm gearings"],
        "answer": "Bevel gears"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an American Standard Screw Threads, what does 6-32 UNC designate?",
        "choices": [
            "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread",
            "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, fine thread",
            "6 inches basic diameter, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread",
            "32 inches basic diameter, 6 threads per inch, coarse thread"
        ],
        "answer": "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread"
    },
    {
        "question": "In gearing, this is the ratio of the arc of action to the circular pitch.",
        "choices": ["Speed ratio", "Arc ratio", "Contact ratio", "Gear ratio"],
        "answer": "Contact ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "This are gears used to connect shafts that are non-intersecting and non-parallel. They are a cross between spriral bevel gears and worm gears.",
        "choices": ["Helical gears", "Hypoid gears", "Planetary gears", "Bevel gears"],
        "answer": "Hypoid gears"
    },
    {
        "question": "AFBMA is an acronym for an association involved in what machine elements?",
        "choices": ["Ball and roller bearings", "Journal bearings", "Flat belts and other belt types", "Any type of gears"],
        "answer": "Ball and roller bearings"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a machine member that supports another part that rotates, slides, or oscillates in or on it.",
        "choices": ["Pulley", "Key", "Bearing", "Shaft"],
        "answer": "Bearing"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a bearing that permits constrained relative motion of rigid parts; lubricant is generally inserted or supplied between the mating surfaces to reduce friction and wear, and to carry away the heat generated.",
        "choices": ["Sliding Contact Bearing", "Rolling Contact Bearing", "Thrust Bearing", "Journal Bearing"],
        "answer": "Sliding Contact Bearing"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bearing where surfaces are non-conformed and motion is primarily rolling; it composed of rolling elements interposed between an outer ring and inner ring.",
        "choices": ["Conformal surfaces bearing", "Sliding-element bearing", "Rolling-element bearing", "Non-conformal surfaces bearing"],
        "answer": "Rolling-element bearing"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a straight bevel gear, how do you call the angle between an element on the pitch cone and an element on the face cone?",
        "choices": ["Face angle", "Pitch angle", "Addendum angle", "Dedendum angle"],
        "answer": "Addendum angle"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a Grashof four-bar mechanism in which the shortest link is the frame or fixed link and the other two cranks completely rotate with their axes. How do you call this Grashof four-bar mechanism?",
        "choices": ["Drag-link mechanism", "Double-rocker mechanism", "Triple-rocker mechanism", "Crank-rocker mechanism"],
        "answer": "Drag-link mechanism"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"For a planar four-bar linkage, the sum of the shortest and longest lengths cannot be greater than the sum of the remaining two link lengths if there is to be a continuous relative rotation between two members.\" How do you call the preceding statement?",
        "choices": ["Grubler's Law", "Coriolli's Law", "Grashof's Law", "Freudentein's Law"],
        "answer": "Grashof's Law"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not true for an instant center or centro of planar linkages?",
        "choices": [
            "Centro is a point common to two bodies having the same velocity in each.",
            "Centro is a point in one body about which another body does not rotate.",
            "Centro is a point in one body about which another body actually turns.",
            "Centro is a point in one body about which another body tends to turn."
        ],
        "answer": "Centro is a point in one body about which another body does not rotate."
    },
    {
        "question": "An element assembled into a tapped hole is",
        "choices": ["key", "nut", "screw", "worm gear"],
        "answer": "screw"
    },
    {
        "question": "In kinematics, the occurrence of linear and rotational motion simultaneously is known as",
        "choices": ["mechanism", "rotakinetics", "corioli's", "Grashof's"],
        "answer": "corioli's"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of the number of teeth to the pitch diameter is",
        "choices": ["circular pitch", "mechanical advantage", "diametral pitch", "Lewi's form factor"],
        "answer": "diametral pitch"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radial distance between the bottomland and the pitch circle is",
        "choices": ["clearance", "dedendum", "addendum", "working depth"],
        "answer": "dedendum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is largely used for low strength applications such as elevator ropes not used to hoisting and for stationary guy ropes",
        "choices": ["steel rope", "cast steel rope", "nylon rope", "iron wire rope"],
        "answer": "iron wire rope"
    },
    {
        "question": "In actual machines",
        "choices": [
            "Mechanical advantage is unity",
            "Mechanical advantage is less than unity",
            "Mechanical advantage is less than velocity ratio",
            "Mechanical advantage is equal to velocity ratio"
        ],
        "answer": "Mechanical advantage is less than velocity ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Used for permanent fits, are similar to involute splines except that the pressure angle is 14.50",
        "choices": ["separation load", "stub serrations", "spline shaft", "involute serrations"],
        "answer": "involute serrations"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gear that has an advantage of smoother engagement, quietness of operation, greater strength and higher permission speeds",
        "choices": ["zerol bevel gear", "straight bevel gear", "hypoid bevel gear", "spiral bevel gear"],
        "answer": "spiral bevel gear"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of which the width of a tooth space exceeds the thickness of engaging tooth is known as",
        "choices": ["tooth space", "circular pitch", "backlash", "flank"],
        "answer": "backlash"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tooth breakage on gear is usually _______.",
        "choices": ["a tensile fatigue", "a contact stress", "a crack", "none of these"],
        "answer": "a tensile fatigue"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the angle through which the gear turns form the time given pair of teeth are in contact at the pitch point until they pass out the mesh",
        "choices": ["angle of contact", "angle of approach", "position angle", "angle of recess"],
        "answer": "angle of recess"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following quick return mechanism is most widely used in most of the slotters",
        "choices": ["Whitworth mechanism", "Hydraulic mechanism", "Slotter disc mechanism", "Slotter link and gear mechanism"],
        "answer": "Whitworth mechanism"
    },
    {
        "question": "The axial distance between specified reference on the internal and external taper thread members",
        "choices": ["pitch", "load", "standoff", "helix distance"],
        "answer": "standoff"
    },
    {
        "question": "The relation between two mating parts with reference to ease the assembly is called",
        "choices": ["allowance", "clearance", "tolerance", "fits"],
        "answer": "fits"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a duplex reciprocating pump:",
        "choices": [
            "the slide valve for the one cylinder is controlled in the piston of the other cylinder",
            "both slide valves operate simultaneously",
            "each slide valve is controlled by its own piston rod",
            "one slide valve operates the other slide valve"
        ],
        "answer": "the slide valve for the one cylinder is controlled in the piston of the other cylinder"
    },
    {
        "question": "Heating above the transformation range, usually 1300F to 1350F, and cooling slowly to soften the metal and increase in machining.",
        "choices": ["Annealing", "Hardening", "Normalizing", "Tempering"],
        "answer": "Annealing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reheating to a temperature below the transformation range, followed by any desired rate of cooling to attain the desired properties of the metal.",
        "choices": ["Annealing", "Hardening", "Normalizing", "Tempering"],
        "answer": "Tempering"
    },
    {
        "question": "Heating to some 100F above the transformation range with subsequent cooling to below that range in still air at room temperature to produce uniform structure of the metal.",
        "choices": ["Annealing", "Hardening", "Normalizing", "Tempering"],
        "answer": "Tempering"
    },
    {
        "question": "Process of forming a metal parts by the use of a powerful pressure from a hammer or press to obtain the desired shape, after the metal has been heated to its plastic range.",
        "choices": ["Rolling", "Forging", "Turning", "Casting"],
        "answer": "Forging"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ability of metal to be deformed considering without rupture.",
        "choices": ["Ductility", "Plasticity", "Malleability", "Elasticity"],
        "answer": "Elasticity"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operation of cooling a heated piece of work rapidly by dipping it in water, brine or oil.",
        "choices": ["Quenching", "Tempering", "Normalizing", "Annealing"],
        "answer": "Quenching"
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of heating a piece of steel to a temperature within or above critical range and cooling rapidly.",
        "choices": ["Normalizing", "Hardening", "Annealing", "Tempering"],
        "answer": "Hardening"
    },
    {
        "question": "The moment of inertial of a rectangle whose base is b and height h about its base is:",
        "choices": ["(bh^3)/12", "(bh^3)/3", "bh/36", "bh/24"],
        "answer": "(bh^3)/12"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stainless steel is obtained by the use of the following alloying element.",
        "choices": ["Chromium", "Tungsten", "Carbon", "Phenol"],
        "answer": "Chromium"
    },
    {
        "question": "An alloy of copper and zinc",
        "choices": ["Chromium", "Brass", "Cast Iron", "Aluminum"],
        "answer": "Brass"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a hardening treatment whereby a cast material is being heated to a very high temperature then suddenly subjected to rapid cooling to improve hardenability or wear resistance is called:",
        "choices": ["normalizing", "tempering", "annealing", "quenching"],
        "answer": "quenching"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unit deformation is also called",
        "choices": ["Torsion", "Strain", "Stresss", "Sprain"],
        "answer": "Strain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Machine used for testing of very thin steel or surface layers.",
        "choices": ["Charpy", "Izod", "Description", "Rockwell"],
        "answer": "Rockwell"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corrosion of iron or iron-based alloys:",
        "choices": ["Rusting", "Crazing", "Chalking", "Fritting"],
        "answer": "Rusting"
    },
    {
        "question": "Change in length per unit length is:",
        "choices": ["Strain", "Stress", "Deformation", "Tensile Strength"],
        "answer": "Strain"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum stress which is reached during tensile testing.",
        "choices": ["stress", "elasticity", "strain", "tensile strength"],
        "answer": "tensile strength"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most abundant engineering material:",
        "choices": ["Steel", "Babbitts", "Aluminum", "Cast Iron"],
        "answer": "Cast Iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "Machine used in testing steel generally strike the speciman from 220 to 265 ft - lb.",
        "choices": ["Izod Test", "Charpy Test", "White Iron", "Malleable Iron"],
        "answer": "White Iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ability of a metal to resist being crushed.",
        "choices": ["fatigue strength", "Bending strength", "Torsional strength", "Compressive Strength"],
        "answer": "Compressive Strength"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ferrous metals contain a relatively large amount of:",
        "choices": ["Manganese", "Carbon", "Sulfur", "Phosphorus"],
        "answer": "Carbon"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flange coupling is:",
        "choices": ["Used for collinear shaft", "Used for non-collinear shaft", "Rigid coupling", "Flexible flange"],
        "answer": "Used for collinear shaft"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ability of metal to stand loads without breaking down.",
        "choices": ["Strain", "Stress", "Elasticity", "Strength"],
        "answer": "Strength"
    },
    {
        "question": "An alloy of tin, copper and a traced amount of phosphorous.",
        "choices": ["Chromium", "Bronze", "Brass", "Aluminum"],
        "answer": "Bronze"
    },
    {
        "question": "This material is the most popular alloy spring steel for conditions involving higher stresses than can be used with the high-carbon steels and for use where fatigue resistance and long endurance are needed; this is also good for shock and impact loads.",
        "choices": ["Chrome silicon", "Chrome vanadium", "hard-drawn wire", "Oil-tempered wire"],
        "answer": "Chrome vanadium"
    }
]